
{
    "sections":[
        {
            "sectionTitle": "General Knowledge",
            "questions":[
                {
                    "questionType":"mcq",
                    "question":"1.Which planet in the solar system is known as the “Red Planet”?",
                    "options":["Venus","Earth","Mars","Jupiter"],
                    "answer":"Mars"
                },
                {
                    "questionType":"text",
                    "question":"What is the capital of Italy?",
                    "answer":"Rome"
                },
                {
                    "questionType":"number",
                    "question":"How many continents are there?",
                    "answer":7
                },
                {
                    "questionType":"mcq",
                    "question":"What is the largest lake in the world?",
                    "options":["Caspian Sea","Baikal","Lake Superior","Ontario"],
                    "answer":"Baikal"
                },
                {
                    "questionType":"mcq",
                    "question":"What gas is used to extinguish fires?",
                    "options":["Oxygen","Nitrogen","Carbon dioxide","Hydrogen"],
                    "answer":"Nitrogen"
                },
                {
                    "questionType":"mcq",
                    "question":"Which of the following planets is not a gas giant?",
                    "options":["Mars","Jupiter","Saturn","Uranus"],
                    "answer":"Mars"
                },
                {
                    "questionType":"number",
                    "question":"How many bones are in the body of an adult human?",
                    "answer":206
                },
                {
                    "questionType":"text",
                    "question":"What is the capital of Japan?",
                    "answer":"Tokyo"
                },
                {
                    "questionType":"mcq",
                    "question":"What animal is the national symbol of Australia?",
                    "options":["Kangaroo","Koala","Emu","Crocodile"],
                    "answer":"Kangaroo"
                },
                {
                    "questionType":"mcq",
                    "question":" For which of these disciplines Nobel Prize is awarded?",
                    "options":["Physics, Chemistry","Physiology","Medicine","All of the above"],
                    "answer":"All of the above"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "sectionTitle":"Science",
            "questions":[
                {
                  "questionType":"mcq",
                  "question":"What type of chemical reactions take place when electricity is passed through water?",
                  "options":["Decomposition","Combination","Displacement","Double Displacement"],
                  "answer":"Decomposition"
                },
                {
                    "questionType":"text",
                    "question":"what is the main function of the cerebrum?",
                    "answer":"Thinking"
                },
                {
                    "questionType":"mcq",
                    "question":"The highest coordinating center in the human body is:",
                    "options":["Kidney","Heart","Brain","Spinal cord"],
                    "answer":"Brain"
                },
                {
                    "questionType":"mcq",
                    "question":"which of the following diseases is not sexually transmitted?",
                    "options":["Syphilis","Gonorrhea","HIV-AIDS","Hepatitis"],
                    "answer":"Hepatitis"
                },
                {
                    "questionType":"mcq",
                    "question":"What is the color of the silver chloride?",
                    "options":["Grey","White","Brown","Greenish"],
                    "answer":"White"
                },
                {
                    "questionType":"mcq",
                    "question":"Which thing changes after the rancidity of food?",
                    "options":["Smell and size","Taste and size","Smell and taste","Taste and shape"],
                    "answer":"Smell and taste"
                },
                {
                    "questionType":"mcq",
                    "question":"Metal oxide + Acid →?",
                    "options":["Salt + Hydrogen",
                    "Metal Hydrate + hydrogen",
                    "Salt + Water",
                    "Metal hydrate + Water"],
                    "answer":"Salt + Water"
                },
                {
                    "questionType":"mcq",
                    "question":"Name the metal which is in liquid form at room temperature?",
                    "options":["Mercury","Gallium","Cesium","Daimond"],
                    "answer":"Mercury"
                },
                {
                    "questionType":"mcq",
                    "question":"Which of the following metal is the most reactive metal?",
                    "options":["Sodium","potassium","Gold","Aluminum"],
                    "answer":"potassium"
                },
                {
                    "questionType":"mcq",
                    "question":"Which of the following metal is not reactive metal?",
                    "options":["Sodium","potassium","Gold","Aluminum"],
                    "answer":"Gold"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "sectionTitle":"Mathematics",
            "questions":[
                {
                    "questionType":"mcq",
                    "question":" Find the Missing Term in Multiples of 6 : 6, 12, 18, 24, _, 36, 42, _ 54, 60.",
                    "options":["32,45","30,48","24,40","25,49"],
                    "answer":"32,48"  
                },
                {
                    "questionType":"mcq",
                    "question":"The Product of 131 × 0 × 300 × 4",
                    "options":["131","300","0","1200"],
                    "answer":"0"
                },
                {
                    "questionType":"mcq",
                    "question":"If David’s age is 27 years old in 2011. What was his age in 2003?",
                    "options":["17","37","19","20"],
                    "answer":"19"
                },
                {
                    "questionType":"mcq",
                    "question":"How Many Months Make a Century?",
                    "options":["1200","12","120","12000"],
                    "answer":"1200"
                },
                {
                    "questionType":"mcq",
                    "question":"What Number Comes Before 9019?",
                    "options":["9099","9091","9109","None of these"],
                    "answer":"None of these"
                },
                {
                    "questionType":"mcq",
                    "question":"How Many Months Have 120 Days?",
                    "options":["12","4","11","2"],
                    "answer":"4"
                },
                {
                    "questionType":"mcq",
                    "question":"Priya had 16 Red Balls, 2 Green Balls, 9  Blue Balls, and 1 Multicolor Ball. If He Lost 9 Red Balls, 1 Green Ball, and 3 Blue Balls. How Many Balls would be Left?",
                    "options":["15","11","28","39"],
                    "answer":"15"
                },
                {
                    "questionType":"mcq",
                    "question":"What is 6% Equals to",
                    "options":["0.06","0.6","0.0006","0.006"],
                    "answer":"0.06"
                },
                {
                    "questionType":"mcq",
                    "question":"How Many Years are there in a Decade?",
                    "options":["5 years","10 years","15 years","20 years"],
                    "answer":"10 years"
                },
                {
                    "questionType":"mcq",
                    "question":"Solve 23 + 3 ÷ 3",
                    "options":["24","25","26","27"],
                    "answer":"24"
                }
            ]

        },
        {
            "sectionTitle":"Indian History",
            "questions":[
                {
                    "questionType":"mcq",
                    "question":"Vallabhi era is identical with which of the following era?",
                    "options":["Vikrama era","Gupta era","Harsha era","None of the above"],
                    "answer":"Gupta era"  
                },
                {
                    "questionType":"mcq",
                    "question":"On the bank of which river, Mahavira attained Kaivalaya?",
                    "options":["Niranjana"," Rijupalika","Yamuna","Jamuna"],
                    "answer":" Rijupalika"
                },
                {
                    "questionType":"mcq",
                    "question":"With which among the following Vedas, the Shatapatha Brahmana is related to___?",
                    "options":["Rigveda","Yajurveda","Samaveda","Atharvaveda"],
                    "answer":"Yajurveda"
                },
                {
                    "questionType":"mcq",
                    "question":"Which among the following current states of India was known as Pragjyotisha in ancient time?",
                    "options":["Assam","Karnataka","Bihar","Gujarath"],
                    "answer":"Assam"
                },
                {
                    "questionType":"mcq",
                    "question":"Who was the first Indo-Greek king, who became Buddhist?",
                    "options":["Menander II","Apollodotus II","Apollodotus I","Antiochus II"],
                    "answer":"Menander II"
                },
                {
                    "questionType":"mcq",
                    "question":"The ancient places of Badami, Dwarasamudra and Warangal are related to which of the following dynasties?",
                    "options":["Chalukyas, Hoysalas, Kaktiyas","Cholas, Hoysalas, Kaktiyas","Pallavas, Hoysalas, Kaktiyas","None of the above"],
                    "answer":"Chalukyas, Hoysalas, Kaktiyas"
                },
                {
                    "questionType":"mcq",
                    "question":"After death of Bindusara, who among the following is considered to help Asoka to capture the throne?",
                    "options":["Radhagupta","Tishya","Bairam khan","Vishnugupta"],
                    "answer":"Radhagupta"
                },
                {
                    "questionType":"mcq",
                    "question":"Which of the following Vedas is sometimes referred as the “Veda of magical formulas”?",
                    "options":["Atharvaveda","Yajurveda","Samveda","Rig-Veda"],
                    "answer":"Atharvaveda"
                },
                {
                    "questionType":"mcq",
                    "question":"In the early Vedic age, Vishnu was one of the names of __?",
                    "options":["Surya","Agni","Dyaus","Prajapati"],
                    "answer":"Surya"
                },
                {
                    "questionType":"mcq",
                    "question":"We have read that the writing in the Indus valley Civilization was Boustrophedon. This means that ______?",
                    "options":["It was written left to right and right to left in alternate lines","It was written up to down","It was written left to right"," It was written right to left"],
                    "answer":"It was written left to right and right to left in alternate lines"
                }
            ]

        }
    ]
}
